Kofi **Forson**

(516)312-6540

ktforson@outlook.com

www.linkedin.com/in/kofi-forson/ in

https://github.com/kof-f

I am a driven Computer Scientist with government experience as a Product Manager and an active TS/SCI security clearance. I manage two software development product teams using Agile and Scrum methodologies and won the highest government civilian engineering award in 2019. In my spare time, I am pursuing my master's degree in Computer Science at Georgia Institute of Technology and furthering my development of a robot to assist the disadvantaged community using Python.

Skills

- Active TS/SCI Security
 Python
- Product Management
- Node.js JavaScript
- Software Development

Robotics

Clearance

- Java
- C++

- Git
- Jira
- Confluence
- Windows
- macOS
- Linux
- CentOS
- Raspbian

Education

EXPECTED: MAY 2021

M.S., Computer Science / Georgia Institute of Technology

GPA: 4.00/4.00

RELEVANT COURSES: Computational Photography, Machine Learning for Trading

GRADUATED: MAY 2018

B.S., Computer Science / Delaware State University

GPA: 3.96/4.00

- RELEVANT COURSES: Elements of Computer Programming, Data Structures and Algorithms, Linear Algebra
- AWARDS: President's Honor List (Spring/Fall 2015, Spring/Fall 2016, Spring/Fall 2017, Spring 2018)
- **SCHOLARSHIPS:** Recipient of SMART Scholarship (first in school history)

Experience

JUL 2018 - PRESENT

Product Manager / Department of Defense - Bedford, MA

- Won the highest engineering award from the digital directorate
- Launched the modernization product team which reduced the data federation workload by 90%
- Operated as Scrum Master for six months and helped reduce the product backlog by 33%
- Full product ownership of two teams, which includes management of all the meeting ceremonies for both teams like the daily stand up calls, weekly backlog grooming meetings, sprint reviews, and sprint retrospectives
- Sprint reviews with stakeholders to ensure both teams are exceeding their software requirements

 Regularly holding design-thinking workshops/conferences to generate design concepts based on user interviews

JAN 2018 - NOV 2019 (PART-TIME)

Lead Developer / Delaware State University - Dover, DE

- Designed a robot using a Raspberry Pi 3 to help the disadvantaged community
- Developed a Python script with object-oriented programming to operate the robot
- Made the robot operable via a DualShock controller by using the pygame module
- Created a <u>repository</u> on GitHub to streamline development of the robot
- Created a webpage marketing the different features of the robot

JUL 2019 - JAN 2020

Developer / Freelance Work - Lowell, MA

- Built several JavaScript projects using APIs, Express and other npm modules
- Developed a weather app using Express and Handlebars
- Developing a task manager REST API with user accounts and authentication

AUG 2014 - MAY 2018

Research Assistant / Delaware State University - Dover, DE

- Won an <u>award</u> at Emerging Researchers National (ERN) Conference for GPU programming research
- Led a research project concerning the decomposition of LIBS protein spectra using fuzzy logic
- Led a research project concerning the benefits of GPU programming on code runtime
- Used pragma statements and GPU programming to improve code runtime by 15%
- Presented research at multiple conferences (SACNAS, ERN)

JUN 2016 - JUN 2016

Systems Engineer / NASA - Wallops Island, VA

- Built a sounding rocket payload in three days with a team of engineers
- Integrated the payload into a sounding rocket which was launched into space
- Recovered the payload post-launch and analyzed the data gathered from space

JAN 2016 - JUN 2016

Systems Engineer / Delaware State University - Dover, DE

- Hacked into an RC car using a Raspberry Pi 2 and L298N motor driver
- Soldered several switches onto the car to switch between different controllers
- Created a Python script to show live video and control the motors of the car
- Documented the entire hack using a WordPress blog

Interesting Facts

- Founder, A Kizzle Brand
- I taught myself Photoshop while in college.
- I enjoy hiking with my girlfriend.
- I jumped off a waterfall in the Dominican Republic.